<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Nikhil Gahlawat</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000"/>
 <updated>2024-07-15T16:00:14-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Nikhil Gahlawat</name>
   <!-- <email></email> -->
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>H-1B Visas and Big Tech</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/h1b-tech/"/>
   <!-- <updated>2024-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated> -->
   <id>http://localhost:4000/projects/h1b-tech</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An independent research project looking at how the tech industry has become increasingly dependent on the H-1B visa, and what that means for the future of the program and the workers it brings to the US.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
  Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikhilgahlawat/immigration-h1b&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; for the code used to clean and analyze the data found in this story.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debate over US immigration policy most often centers on the southern border where every day thousands of migrants attempt enter the country without prior authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But advocates, lawmakers, and business leaders are also fighting a pitched battle over legal immigration programs, the most contentious of which may be the H-1B visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to border crossings, the number of H-1Bs is relatively small. While there were 2.5 million migrant encounters at the border in 2023, only around 120,000 new H-1B visas were issued that same year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its relative size belies its importance, though. Foreign guest workers have an outsized impact on the US economy, and on one industry in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology companies have been claiming a larger share of available H-1B visas each year. In 2023, tech companies received 4x as many visas compared to 15 years earlier, and half of the 10 largest H-1B recipients were companies in the tech industry. Since 2015, 20 of the largest tech companies have formally declared dependency on the program at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech’s growing reliance on the H-1Bs pits two competing factors against one another: the desire to remain globally competitive in critical technologies and an emerging isolationism eager to close the border and protect US workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tension scrambles the normal political divides. Far-right Republicans fighting to shut down the border find themselves on the same side as pro-labor progressives arguing to pare down a program they believe harms US workers. Meanwhile, free-market conservatives as well as Democrats with close ties to the tech industry want to open the gates wider by eliminating visa limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any reform will have far-reaching consequences. Some of the companies most reliant on H-1B visas are at the center of a battle for global dominance in critical technologies. And foreign workers who wish to stay in the US after their visas expire are placed in an overstuffed green card backlog where the wait time is sometimes measured in decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calls for reform are mounting. The future of the H-1B program - and the guest workers at its heart - remains uncertain, but there are clues as to where it may be heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-outsourcing-visa-goes-to-silicon-valley&quot;&gt;The ‘outsourcing visa’ goes to Silicon Valley&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For nearly 35 years, the H-1B visa has been the primary avenue for US companies to hire high-skilled foreign workers. Designed as a temporary guest worker program, H-1Bs allow workers from abroad to stay in the US for three years with the option to renew for another three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program has been wildly popular with employers. Every year, tens of thousands of companies petition U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) for one or more H-1B visas. Most companies are subject to a cap that limits the total number of new visas each year to 85,000. The USCIS almost always recieves more petitions than available slots - sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cato.org/blog/h-1b-lottery-results-announced-3/4-rejected&quot;&gt;nearly 9-times&lt;/a&gt; as many - leaving them to run a lottery to determine which companies get to hire foreign workers. On top of that, nonprofit research organizations, universities, and teaching hospitals are exempt from the cap, meaning the number of new visas each year usually far exceeds 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with that popularity has come intense criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While H-1Bs are accessible to most employers, two industries have dominated the program: IT &amp;amp; professional services staffing firms and tech companies. Over the past 15 years, a quarter of all H-1Bs have gone to just 20 companies, all but one of which are in these industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, the primary charge levied against H-1B visas was that companies use the program to outsource US jobs overseas. The concern, voiced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z2dR4Z6dRIo&quot;&gt;Democrats&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/nov/21/tech-workers-visas-h-1b-reduction-trump-administration&quot;&gt;Republicans&lt;/a&gt; alike, was that H-1Bs enable a kind of parasitic business model: companies source cheap labor abroad, make their US employees train the guest workers, send the guest workers back overseas once their visas expire, and finally fire the US workers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/04/us/last-task-after-layoff-at-disney-train-foreign-replacements.html&quot;&gt;replacing them&lt;/a&gt; with their freshly trained, less expensive foreign counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not always following this playbook exactly, companies like Infosys, Tata Consultancy Services, and Cognizant - often headquartered abroad - built their businesses around hoovering up huge swaths of the limited H-1B pool and then contracting these workers to other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, just 30 outsourcing companies claimed nearly 48,000 H-1B visas, over half of the 85,000 cap. The program was so dominated by these companies that one Indian government official referred to H-1Bs as the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2007/04/15/business/yourmoney/15view.html&quot;&gt;outsourcing visa&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/h1b_tech_top_employers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Top H-1B employers in 2009 and 2023&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite both parties calling for reform over the years, it wasn’t until the Trump administration’s crusade against both illegal and legal immigration that tides began to shift. With its “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uscis.gov/archive/buy-american-and-hire-american-putting-american-workers-first&quot;&gt;Buy American and Hire American&lt;/a&gt;” policy, the USCIS began rejecting H-1B visa applications en masse. The overall denial rate for both new H-1B visas and renewals doubled in 2018, up to 15% from 7% the year before. The policy hit outsourcing companies hardest. Their denial rate, just 5% in 2017, shot up to 22% in 2018 and peaked at 24% in 2019. First-time guest workers were the primary target. The Trump administration rejected 1 out of every 3 new visa applications by outsourcing companies in both 2018 and 2019, and nearly 1 out of every 4 in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/H-1B Visa Denial Rates.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Visa Denial Rates&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/H-1B Visa Denial Rates for Outsourcing Companies.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Visa Denial Rates&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While outsourcing companies reeled from the administration’s crackdown, tech companies were barely touched. Denial rates for the largest tech companies remained essentially flat, peaking at just 3% in 2019. Instead, big tech companies doubled their volume of H-1B visa approvals during the Trump years. Over the 15 year period from 2009 to 2023, total visa approvals for big tech companies were up over 300%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/H-1B Visa Approvals - Outsourcing Companies.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Visa Approvals - Outsourcing Companies&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/H-1B Visa Approvals - Tech Companies.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Visa Approvals - Tech Companies&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industry was growing increasingly reliant on H-1B visas. So much so that more and more tech firms became “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dol.gov/agencies/whd/fact-sheets/62c-h1b-dependent-employer&quot;&gt;H-1B dependent&lt;/a&gt;,” a declaration made by employers to the Department of Labor that at least 15% of their workforce are on H-1B visas, a distinction which had mostly been reserved for outsourcing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/h1b_dependent_outsourcing.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Dependent Outsourcing&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/h1b_dependent_tech.png&quot; alt=&quot;H-1B Dependent Tech&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most notably, Meta has been H-1B dependent every year since 2015, as far back as data is available. And Nvidia, the semiconductor and AI company jockeying with Microsoft for the title of world’s most valuable company, has been H-1B dependent since 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nvidia’s reliance on foreign guest workers in particular may signal the importance H-1Bs will play in the future not just of the tech industry, but in US politics more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-politics-of-reform&quot;&gt;The politics of reform&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2022, Congress passed the CHIPS and Science Act which included &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/7/28/23282494/semiconductors-chips-and-science-act-joe-biden-congress-nvidia&quot;&gt;$52 billion&lt;/a&gt; for semiconductor manufacturing in the US. Motivated by a bipartisan opposition to China’s rising dominance in the field, lawmakers united hoping to capitalize on a global chip shortage by reigniting an industry the US had originally pioneered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semiconductor companies are already heavily leveraging H-1Bs. Of the 20 large tech companies declaring H-1B dependence at least once since 2015, 11 are in the semiconductor industry. And though not H-1B dependent, Intel, one of the largest US semiconductor companies, ranks 15th among the biggest beneficiaries of the H-1B program since 2009, securing approval for almost 32,000 visas over the past 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech companies have long &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/may/05/us-tech-firms-visas-hillary-clinton-donald-trump-immigration&quot;&gt;lobbied&lt;/a&gt; Washington to make hiring foreign workers easier. Adding new investments and pitched global competition into the mix means calls to expand the H-1B program will likely intensify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race for dominance in semiconductors places the H-1B program at the intersection of US immigration and foreign policy, potentially complicating the politics of reform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economic populism is uniting the left and right against H-1Bs. Pro-labor groups have long been skeptical of the visa, arguing that it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epi.org/publication/h-1b-visas-and-prevailing-wage-levels/&quot;&gt;drives down wages&lt;/a&gt; for domestic workers. This finds them on perhaps awkward common ground with the far right who decry foreign labor as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/18/us/politics/executive-order-hire-buy-american-h1b-visa-trump.html&quot;&gt;theft&lt;/a&gt;” from US workers. Both parties have also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/14/us/politics/biden-china-tariffs.html&quot;&gt;supported tariffs&lt;/a&gt; in a sign of declining enthusiasm for free trade, including the free movement of labor across borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, international rivalry - especially with China - is one of the only things &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/8/9/23298147/biden-chips-act-semiconductors-subsidies-ohio-arizona-plant-china&quot;&gt;driving&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/senate-overwhelmingly-passes-aid-for-ukraine-israel-and-taiwan-in-big-bipartisan-vote&quot;&gt;bipartisan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/13/technology/tiktok-ban-house-vote.html&quot;&gt;action&lt;/a&gt;. H-1B reform may be no different. Lawmakers on both sides are &lt;a href=&quot;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/visa-and-immigration/legislation-introduced-in-us-senate-to-reform-and-stop-abuse-of-h-1b-visa-system/articleshow/89960231.cms&quot;&gt;already uniting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the tech industry’s emergence as a prominent user of H-1B visas, many of the proposed changes are likely to continue hitting outsourcing companies hardest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because wages are often at the center of proposed reforms, whether attempting to raise wage requirements for employers that hire H-1Bs or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.durbin.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/durbin-grassley-to-dhs-implement-h1-b-visa-program-reforms&quot;&gt;revamping&lt;/a&gt; the lottery system to give employers offering higher wages a better chance of winning a visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 15 years, 72% of workers hired by outsourcing companies have fallen into the two lowest allowable wage categories. Meanwhile, the biggest tech companies have hired only 54% of their H-1B workers into these categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech also pays their H-1B workers better. In 2023, the median annual wage for H-1Bs in big tech was 60% higher than at outsourcing companies: $153,000 compared to $96,000, and $113,000 for all other companies. Even the workers in the lowest wage categories make substantially more in tech compared to outsourcing, $108,000 to $66,000 respectively. Wages for H-1Bs in tech have also grown faster compared to outsourcing companies, up 33% since 2015 compared to 26% for outsourcing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/projects/assets/h1b-tech/Median Wages for H-1B Workers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Median Wages for H-1B Workers&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;line-height:-2; font-size:10pt; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;
Wages are grouped into levels based on how they compare to the local median wage of similar occupations.&lt;br /&gt;
Level 1: 17th percentile of local median wage | Level 2: 34th perc | Level 3: 50th perc | Level 4: 67th perc
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If reforms do pass, they will likely continue targeting outsourcing companies, clearing the way for big tech to continue claiming more of the visa pool, as they have been over the past 15 years. But H-1B reform alone deals only with which foreign workers get to come to the US. What happens after they’re here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lottery-winners-in-limbo&quot;&gt;Lottery winners in limbo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While H-1B visas authorize foreign workers to stay in the US for 3-6 years, many can and do apply for permanent residency, which lets them continue working while their case winds through the immigration system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That can take years, even decades. In 2021, there were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cato.org/blog/14-million-skilled-immigrants-employment-based-green-card-backlogs-2021&quot;&gt;1.4 million&lt;/a&gt; employment-based visa cases applying for permanent residency. Backlogs are especially long for workers from countries that supply the most H-1B workers. Nearly 3 out of every 4 approved visas that year were granted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uscis.gov/sites/default/files/document/data/H1B_Characteristics_Congressional_Report_FY2021-3.2.22.pdf&quot;&gt;workers from India&lt;/a&gt;. The estimated wait time for permanent residency for an Indian applicant is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cato.org/blog/14-million-skilled-immigrants-employment-based-green-card-backlogs-2021&quot;&gt;46 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H-1B visas are also tied to employers, not the guest worker. That means that if the worker wants to change jobs - or loses their job - they have to find another employer willing to hire them and pay &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/us-immigration-agency-will-lose-millions-process-visas-fast-enough&quot;&gt;thousands of dollars&lt;/a&gt; to apply for a visa. If the worker can’t find new employment within 60 days, they have to leave the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding that new company may be getting more difficult too. The number of employers receiving H-1B visas is declining, down around 20% since 2009. Meanwhile, the number of visas issued is growing, up around 70% in that same time period. More workers at the whim of fewer employers, increasingly concentrated in a single industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when that industry goes through rocky times, as the tech industry did in 2022 and 2023, those workers compete for new jobs at the same time. Some of the companies with the most H-1B workers laid off the most employees. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://layoffs.fyi/&quot;&gt;Layoffs.fyi&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon has laid off over 27,000 workers since 2022. Meta has laid off 21,000. Google has laid off over 13,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there’s no widely available data on how many of those let go were on H-1B visas, Layoffs.fyi does provide crowdsourced lists of individuals who lost their jobs, mostly as visibility for recruiters who might be hiring. The list for two companies, TikTok and Tesla, provide a space for workers to indicate whether they require sponsorship from their next employer. Of those who completed the field, roughly a quarter said they would need sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for H-1B workers who are spared a pink slip, a company suffering enough to cut labor may demand more work and longer hours from those who remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Twitter cut nearly half its workforce in November 2022, Elon Musk &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/16/23462026/elon-musk-twitter-email-hardcore-or-severance&quot;&gt;demanded&lt;/a&gt; that the remaining workers commit to “extremely hardcore” conditions of “long hours at high intensity,” otherwise leave. To the roughly 350 H-1B workers the company authorized that year and hundreds more from years prior, whose alternative was to find another job within 60 days or leave the country, such a demand might sound like extortion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When weighing their options, H-1B workers have to consider not just themselves but their families. The visa allows spouses and dependents to accompany the guest worker, but their statuses are tied together. This can leave entire families - sometimes waiting decades for permanent residency - to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/19/technology/h1-b-tech-worker-life.html&quot;&gt;build their lives&lt;/a&gt; in a liminal status: spending more time away from the country they may be forced to return to, and building a life in one that may not let them stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children of H-1B workers can live almost their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/adult-children-of-work-visa-recipients-forced-to-return-to-parents-countries-11654596000?mod=hp_lead_pos10&quot;&gt;entire lives&lt;/a&gt; in the US and then, if their parents lose sponsorship, be forced to return to a country to which they have little connection. Children can also age out of the program and be forced to leave. While they recently received &lt;a href=&quot;https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/work/us-senate-announces-plan-to-provide-100k-work-authorisation-to-spouses-and-children-of-h-1b-visa-holders/articleshow/107420992.cms&quot;&gt;some relief&lt;/a&gt;, lawmakers have yet to give children of H-1B workers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/stuartanderson/2024/06/13/dhs-uscis-urged-to-protect-green-card-applicants-and-their-children/&quot;&gt;full protection&lt;/a&gt;. Their best option is to enter the H-1B lottery themselves, and if selected start the whole cycle over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this adds up to a paradigm that funnels foreign workers into a system that can keep them and their families in indefinite limbo with little recourse. A system that the tech industry is increasingly banking on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;walls-and-cages&quot;&gt;Walls and cages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of what to do with the H-1B program remains a thorny corner of immigration reform, one that often gets lost amid the border crisis. In 2016, Donald Trump campaigned on building a wall to keep out would-be immigrants. Not long after, the U.S. Border Patrol’s “zero tolerance” policy put &lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/9794de32d39d4c6f89fbefaea3780769&quot;&gt;families in cages&lt;/a&gt;. Against images like these, little else can stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the battle against immigrants has not been waged solely on those trying to enter the country without authorization. Even those who seek out legal channels have been met with a bureaucratic ticket so dense with paperwork and fees and fickle discretion that some describe it as an “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.propublica.org/article/authorities-can-now-deny-visa-and-green-card-applications-without-giving-applicants-a-chance-to-fix-errors&quot;&gt;invisible wall&lt;/a&gt;” purposely designed to quietly keep people out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through it all, though, the H-1B program has served as a reliable pathway for foreign workers eager to find opportunity and prosperity in the US. But the program is increasingly under strain and scrutiny, with conflicting calls for reform coming from all sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As things stand, the situation may be unsustainable. Workers labor under the specter of deportation whenever the economy dips, and they along with their families are asked to build lives waiting for green cards that may never come. The H-1B program and employment-based visa system are meant to be a gap in the invisible wall, but an overloaded system and endless backlogs pave a path into something that may resemble more of an invisible cage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst all of this, H-1B workers have become cornerstones of an industry building technologies of global importance, waiting for a permanent place in a country whose future they’re working to secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scraping the Supreme Court</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/scotus-scraper/"/>
   <!-- <updated>2024-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated> -->
   <id>http://localhost:4000/projects/scotus-scraper</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikhilgahlawat/scotus_scraper/&quot;&gt;SCOTUS Scraper&lt;/a&gt; is a project to collect US Supreme Court opinions, briefs, and other documents filed with the Court and make them available in machine-readable format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/24/us/supreme-court-abortion-briefs.html&quot;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; about new research that takes an NLP-like approach to understanding how arguments are presented before the Supreme Court. The researchers collected amicus briefs filed in cases having to do with the same topic - in this case, reproductive rights - and analyzed their text to see how the arguments changed over time, and what that might indicate about how rhetorical strategies have evolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they found that opponents to abortion had done a better job of adapting their strategies over time, making efforts to match the way the Court itself was changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was curiuos to dig a bit deeper into the analysis. See what methods they used and if they could be applied to other issues commonly brought before the Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I looked through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholarship.law.missouri.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=4664&amp;amp;context=mlr&quot;&gt;full paper&lt;/a&gt; I saw that they’d limited their analysis to reproductive rights, and they hadn’t made the data available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went digging around the internet in search of a dataset of Supreme Court opinions text, and had a surprisingly difficult time finding one. There were some datasets on how justices voted, data on lower and state courts, data on caselaw, and even a couple resources that had the text of oral arguments. Here are a few interesting resources I found along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scdb.wustl.edu/&quot;&gt;Supreme Court Database&lt;/a&gt; from Washington University Law&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://case.law/&quot;&gt;Caselaw Access Project&lt;/a&gt; from Harvard Law School&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://convokit.cornell.edu/documentation/supreme.html&quot;&gt;Supreme Court Oral Arguments Corpus&lt;/a&gt; from ConvoKit made by researchers at Cornell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://free.law/projects/supreme-court-data&quot;&gt;Supreme Court Data&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://free.law/&quot;&gt;Free Law Project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.courtlistener.com/&quot;&gt;CourtListener&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I couldn’t seem to find what I was looking for: a freely available dataset of Supreme Court opinions text in machine-readable format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried making it myself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikhilgahlawat/scotus_scraper/tree/main&quot;&gt;SCOTUS Scraper&lt;/a&gt; is a project in-progreess that collects data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://supreme.justia.com/&quot;&gt;Justia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oyez.org/&quot;&gt;Oyez&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.supremecourt.gov/&quot;&gt;US Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; and processes them into datasets that can be used for data science and research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some analses I’m hoping can be done with the data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare amicus briefs and opinions to see if certain organizations that frequently submit briefs are more influential than others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare amicus briefs and opinions to see whether certain justices more influenced by amicus briefs than others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analyze the content of influential amicus briefs to understand what makes them persuasive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify and compare rhetorical strategies used in majority opinions, dissenting opinions, and amicus briefs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Examine how consistent justices are in their rulings over time, particularly in cases involving similar legal principles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify instances where justices have changed their stance on key issues and analyze the potential reasons for these shifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing project so I’m hoping to add more features and additional data. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nikhilgahlawat/scotus_scraper/&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
